Ambitious web developer brings enthusiasm and detailed understanding of various programming languages to webpage planning, development and maintenance with a problem-solving approach. Experience designing and developing sites from concept to roll out. Innate ability to communicate with project manager to ascertain web marketing needs and design interface that accommodates specifications. Deep understanding of various CSS and HTML options, plugins, development platforms and security requirements according to up-to-date standards. Data-driven individual with excellent grasp of Google Analytics and other search optimization needs. Brings background in graphic arts, coding, media integration, and SEO to accomplish tasks.

Accomplishments

- Air Force Achievement Medal received July 2012.
- Supervised team of 6 staff members.
- Resolved product issue through consumer testing.
- Spearheaded a large-scale client project as a result of skill set and education and completed the project two weeks ahead of schedule.

Work History

2020-12

2015-02 - Firefighter

Department of the ARMY, Fort Hood, TX

- Responded to emergency medical calls to perform lifesaving procedures and other emergency medical services.
- Calmly and effectively directed evacuations during fires and emergencies to avoid fatalities, injuries and panic.
- Strengthened organizational intranet program and sub-sites to bolster internal communication strategies.
- Investigated and corrected problems with printers, copiers and other peripheral devices.
- Delivered network technology training to junior team members and end-users, enhancing knowledgebase and team productivity.
- Set up hardware and software in optimal configurations to meet network performance requirements.
- Established, repaired and optimized networks by installing wiring, cabling and devices.
- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up workstations for employees.

CHARLES MILLER

Web Developer

Contact

Phone

(662) 251-5388

E-mail

charles.miller.0412@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/charlesmiller0412

Portfolio

www.charlesmiller.dev

Skills

Search Engine Optimization

Web Design

Lifecycle Management

Brand Management

Testing and maintenance

User Data Collection

Git Version Control

Code debugging

UI improvements

Requirements gathering

UX/UI Design

Firefighter / Supervisory 911 Dispatcher

2008-08 -

United States Air Force, Elmendorf AFB, AK

- Received public emergency and non-emergency calls and supervised response prioritization in order to effectively dispatch official units such as police, fire and EMS while tracking data in real-time environments.
- Automated document flow by ensuring logbooks and fire, accident and emergency reports were maintained with 100% accuracy.
- Read system maps and caller information and documented all details in system.
- Actively listened to customers, handled concerns quickly and escalated major issues to supervisor.
- Saved approximately \$3,000,000 by implementing cost-saving initiatives that addressed long-standing problems.
- Supervised and assisted with the implementation of new multimillion-dollar E911 system and department wide CAD system.
- Became supervisor of Emergency Communications at the rank of E-3, usually a position held by an E-5 or above.

Education

2018-08 -

Current

Bachelor of Science: Internet and Web Development

Arizona State University - Tempe, AZ

- Dean's List Fall 2020 and Spring 2021
- Coursework in Web Development, UX/UI Design, and Graphic Design
- Currently holding 3.62 GPA

2015-01 -2017-12

Associate of Science: Fire and Emergency Services Technology

University of Alaska Anchorage - Anchorage, AK

